<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Movable-Type | www.Tallinna.Ru</title>
    <link>/tag/movable-type/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tag/movable-type/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Movable-Type</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>ru</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Jul 2008 05:42:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Movable-Type</title>
      <link>/tag/movable-type/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Приветствие!</title>
      <link>/2008/07/privetstvie.php/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jul 2008 05:42:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/2008/07/privetstvie.php/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font style=&#34;font-size: 1.25em;&#34;&gt;Приветствую&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;всех&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;u&gt;кто&lt;/u&gt; &lt;strike&gt;пометил&lt;/strike&gt; посетил &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dmitrijev.ru/&#34;&gt;мою домашнюю страничку&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Расширенный текст&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Я установил Movable 4!</title>
      <link>/2008/07/ja-ustanovil-movable-4.php/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jul 2008 05:33:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/2008/07/ja-ustanovil-movable-4.php/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Добро пожаловать в мой новый блог, созданный на платформе Movable Type. Это первая запись, она была создана для меня автоматически, когда закончился процесс установки. Уже скоро я создам собственные записи!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 class=&#34;asset-name&#34;&gt;Movable Type 4 installation step by step with screenshots&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;b&gt;Quick instructions how to install Movable Type 4 publishing platform - step by step with screenshots!&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The
new and cool blog system is out - Movable Type 4, and i&#39;m giving you
short and clear instructions how to install that thingee. It&#39;s easy,
trust me!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;OK, here&#39;s what you do in order to get your MT4 blog up and running:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Server data&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Download&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Unzip&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Upload&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Chmod&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Install&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Configure&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Log in ;)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h1 class=&#34;asset-name&#34;&gt;1. Before you start,&lt;/h1&gt;Log
into your hosting accound (your server admin panel) and create a new
SQL database, copy database name, database username, database username
password (and in some cases, if the &#39;database server&#39; is not
&#39;localhost&#39; write it down too, as far as i know GoDaddy service has
this issue). You will need that data to enter later installing you
blog. Don&#39;t know how to get this data? Huh, ask a guru to help you, for
example some geek-friend or e-mail your hosting provider, they will
help.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h1 class=&#34;asset-name&#34;&gt;2. Download Movable Type 4,&lt;/h1&gt;And make sure you&#39;ve got the latest stable version of MT4, go to official website &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.movabletype.com/&#34; title=&#34;Movable Type&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;www.movabletype.com&lt;/a&gt;,
go to &#34;Download/Buy&#34;, click &#34;Free Personal License&#34; and choose the
operating system you have (tar.gz for non-Windows folks, zip for Bill
Gates fans) and select language you want your new shiny blog to be (i
guess it&#39;s English). Don&#39;t forget to check the &#34;I accept ...&#34; bla bla
(oh, you can read it to..). Now save that file to your computer.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h1 class=&#34;asset-name&#34;&gt;3. Unzip that file,&lt;/h1&gt;It&#39;s
about 11 mb in size when unzipped. That&#39;s OK, most of &#39;normal&#39; hosting
providers give you way more space than you&#39;ll ever need.&lt;br /&gt;I suggest to use WinRar
as a software for unzipping - it&#39;s quick and intuitive. Then you&#39;ll
have a folder full of CGI files and other folders - this is the stuff
you will upload to your hosting.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h1 class=&#34;asset-name&#34;&gt;4. Now upload files&lt;/h1&gt;that are in this folder (something like &#34;MT-4.0-en&#34;). I use FileZilla
for fast and easy FTP uploads, it&#39;s really cool soft! It supports
drag-and-drop function, just log into your hosting server (the root
directory &#34;yoursite.com&#34; or any other new directory, let&#39;s say
&#34;yoursite.com.com/blog/&#34; ), select all files on you computer and
drag&#39;em over to server. If you don&#39;t have a broadband internet at home,
it will take time to upload them eleven megabytes, so go and make some
tea with cookies, would you.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h1 class=&#34;asset-name&#34;&gt;5. Now chmod them files,&lt;/h1&gt;As
you can read in the MT4 installation &#39;readme&#39; file. Don&#39;t panic,
&#39;chmod&#39; is nothing else than just selecting files and changing
properties.&lt;br /&gt;You might have some problems with changing the
properties of files if you server is in Pentagon or some place else
where admin has put more than paranoia into security settings. &lt;b&gt;If so - get in touch with your hosting provider and ask for instructions or permissions.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h1 class=&#34;asset-name&#34;&gt;6. It&#39;s time to install,&lt;/h1&gt;Now
enter you address where you uploaded files into your browser
(&#34;yoursite.com&#34; or &#34;yoursite.com/blog/&#34; or whatever you did), it will
bring up screen like this:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Wait some 5 or 10 seconds and it will automatically reload it to start your installation:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Now it will check is everything OK with your sever settings:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Now enter server data you have already (you have it, do you?..), and click &#39;test connection&#39;:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Wow, you did it, everything&#39;s OK with database, now proceed:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Now
it asks for mail configuration, no problemo! Choose &#34;sendmail&#34; and
enter YOURS e-mail so you can test if it works. Click &#39;send test email&#39;
and check you inbox. Now continue installation:&lt;br /&gt;You&#39;re almost done. Configuration file is created and click &#39;continue&#39;:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h1 class=&#34;asset-name&#34;&gt;7. Here you must create&lt;/h1&gt;your login data. You&#39;re the admin, so enter whatever you want to. Just make sure you dont misspell e-mail and remember password:&lt;br /&gt;Next step you enter basic info about your blog. Name, URL - choose
directory where you uploaded MT4 files, like &#34;yoursite.com.com/blog/&#34;
(or leave only &#34;yoursite.com&#34; if you have no separate blog directory
(delete the last part &#34;/my-first-blog/&#34; if it automatically shows up in
URL and Publishing Path forms). You may also choose time zone. Now
click &#34;Finish install&#34;, click it!!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Something smart like this will show up:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And then it will tell you that installation is complete and you&#39;re done!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h1 class=&#34;asset-name&#34;&gt;8. Now you can log in&lt;/h1&gt;By
clicking &#39;sign in...&#34;, it will take you to admin area and here&#39;s where
you start to explore Movable Type 4 blogging platform Movable Type
admin dashboard is accessible anywhere by entering this URL -
&#34;www.yoursite.com/mt.cgi&#34;) . &lt;br /&gt;Browse around, change some settings, check out cool templates it has by default, it&#39;s yours, play!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I&#39;ve been using WordPress for a while, so i got curious about MT4 - is
it worth to try it? Yes, it is. Is it better than WordPress? No, i&#39;d
say they&#39;re equal.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;WordPress seems to have more plugins and
templates, as a result of that big open source community that is
involved in making of this blog platform. On the other hand, Movable
Type 4 comes with some handy features already out-of-the-box, whereas
on WordPress you have to install them as separate plug-ins.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
You can get some bits of information about Movable Type 4 Beta .
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Cheers,&lt;br /&gt;Nakamura.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;P.S. if the lazy
monkey inside my head will not take over, i might post some more
Movable Type 4 tips and tricks, feel free to bookmark me!&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
