<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Movable-Type | Dmitrijev.ru</title><link>https://dmitrijev.ru/category/movable-type/</link><atom:link href="https://dmitrijev.ru/category/movable-type/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Movable-Type</description><generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>ru</language><copyright>© Vladimir Dmitrijev 2003-2020</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2008 04:23:42 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://dmitrijev.ru/images/icon_hu4f7f1b8434ceb601df928cdf3e46831d_46965_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url><title>Movable-Type</title><link>https://dmitrijev.ru/category/movable-type/</link></image><item><title>Облако русских тэгов для MT</title><link>https://dmitrijev.ru/2008/07/oblako-russkix-tegov-dlja-mt.php/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2008 04:23:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dmitrijev.ru/2008/07/oblako-russkix-tegov-dlja-mt.php/</guid><description>&lt;p>Заметил, что при обозначении Тэгов на кириллице (например, Тэг:&lt;i> Блог&lt;/i>) - Облако их считает Отдельными «облачками», а не одним Большим Облаком&amp;hellip;&lt;br />После перевода (редактирования) на английский - Облако отображается верно&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Уверен, что для русской версии есть решение. Найду напишу здесь. Возможная причина это то, что данный скрипт (движок этого сайта) - это смесь &lt;i>&lt;b>MTOS-4.1-ru-RC1&lt;/b>&lt;/i> и &lt;i>&lt;b>MTP-4.12-en&lt;/b>&lt;/i> и поэтому не всё отображается корректно&amp;hellip;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Установка Movable Type 4 шаг за шагом со скриншотами</title><link>https://dmitrijev.ru/2008/07/ustanovka-movable-type-4-shag.php/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jul 2008 08:42:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dmitrijev.ru/2008/07/ustanovka-movable-type-4-shag.php/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;span class="byline">От &lt;a href="http://www.superxm.com/">Nakamura&lt;/a>. В моем переводе. С небольшими дополнениями и изменениями. По этой
инструкции, с дополнением под моего хостера, удалось запустить MT.
Оригинал расположен здесь -&lt;/span> &lt;a href="http://www.superxm.com/2007/08/movable-type-4-installation-step-by-step-with-screenshots.html">Movable Type 4 installation step by step with screenshots&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Вышла новая, хорошая платформа для ведения блогов - &lt;i>Movable Type 4&lt;/i> и
эта короткая и простая инструкция поможет вам установить этот движок.
Это просто, поверьте!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Вот все, что вам необходимо для этого сделать:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>&lt;li>Подготовить базу данных&lt;/li>&lt;li>Скачать&lt;/li>&lt;li>Разархивировать&lt;/li>&lt;li>Загрузить&lt;/li>&lt;li>Изменить атрибуты файлов&lt;/li>&lt;li>Установить&lt;/li>&lt;li>Сконфигурировать&lt;/li>&lt;li>Войти&amp;nbsp; &lt;/li>&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;span id="more-314">&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;b>1. Прежде чем начать&lt;/b>, зайдите в административную панель вашего
хостера, и создайте новую SQL базу данных. Скопируйте куда-нибудь себе
инофрмацию о созданной базе данных - &lt;i>database name, database username,
database username password&lt;/i> и в некоторых случаях '&lt;i>database server&lt;/i>' - не
у всех хостеров это '&lt;i>localhost'&lt;/i>. Все эти данные вам понадобятся немного
позже. Вы не знаете о чем речь? Тогда попросите помощи у вашего
компьютерного Гуру, у друзей или у вашего хостера. Они скорее
всего вам смогут помочь.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;b>2. Скачайте Movable Type 4&lt;/b>, и чтобы быть уверенным что у вас последняя, стабильная версия MT4, скачивайте с официального сайта &lt;a href="http://www.movabletype.com/" title="Movable Type 4">http://www.movabletype.com/&lt;/a>
идите там в раздел "&lt;i>Download/Buy&lt;/i>" и жмите там "&lt;i>Free Personal License&lt;/i>" и
выбирайте файл соотвтетственно вашей операционной системе (как правило
Windows). Затем выберите язык, тут пожалуй кроме Английского выбирать
то и нечего для нас. Не забудьте поставить галочку возле "I accept ..." и
загрузите файл на ваш компьютер.&lt;br />&lt;img alt="Movable Type 4" src="http://www.superxm.com/images/mt4-installation-01.jpg" class="border" />&lt;br />&lt;/p>&lt;p>3&lt;b>. Разархивируйте этот файл&lt;/b>. В развернутом виде он будет занимать 11
мегабайт. Чтобы разархивировать скачанный архив, вы можете
воспользоваться программой &lt;a href="http://www.rarlab.com/">WinRar&lt;/a>. После того, как вы разархивируете, у вас вместо одного файла получится много других файлов и папок.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="http://www.superxm.com/images/mt4-installation-02.jpg" height="99" width="307" />&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="http://www.superxm.com/images/mt4-installation-03.jpg" height="99" width="307" />&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="http://www.superxm.com/images/mt4-installation-04.jpg" height="510" width="356" />&lt;/p>
&lt;p>И.. Если ваш блог расположен на серверах GoDaddy, прежде чем
приступать к следующему пункту, необходимо произвести некоторые
изменения. Во всех файлах с расширением cgi необходимо поменять первую
строчк, которая должна будет выглядеть после изменения следующим
образом -&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;i>&lt;code>#!/usr/bin/perl -w -I/path/to/mt_dir/lib&lt;/code>&lt;/i>&lt;/pre>
&lt;pre>&lt;i>где &lt;code>/path/to/mt_dir/lib - полный путь к директории lib&lt;/code>&lt;/i>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>Чтобы не мучатся и не делать это все ручками, воспользуйтесь программой &lt;a href="http://www.rjlsoftware.com/software/utility/search/">Simple Search-Replace&lt;/a>:&lt;/p>&lt;br />&lt;p>Где&lt;i> Path to search&lt;/i> укажите путь к вашему разархивированному архиву.
Поставьте галочку в &lt;i>Search Subdirectories&lt;/i> чтобы изменения были сделаны
действительно во всех файлах. Притом необходимо чтобы изменения были
сделаны именно в файлах &lt;b>cgi&lt;/b>, на что указывает строка &lt;i>File types&lt;/i>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;i>Find what text&lt;/i> - тут у меня не было под рукой оригинала, поэтому
лучше откройте текстовым редактором любой файл cgi и скопируйте первую
строчку с этим текстом целиком. Ставим галочку в &lt;i>Replace with&lt;/i> и
изменяем строку на требуемую нам с указанием пути который у вас будет
на севрере к директории &lt;b>lib&lt;/b> (для &lt;i>Movable Type&lt;/i> естественно) какой он у
вас будет. Только учтите, что в этой строчке у меня по ошибке пропущено
# и поэтому в этом плане скриншот некорректный. Затем проверяем что все
сделали правильно, нажимаем в окне программы на &lt;i>Start&lt;/i>. И после того,
как замена будет произведена (только если ваш хостер GoDaddy),
переходим к нашему следующему пункту.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;b>4. Теперь осталось загрузить файлы на сервер&lt;/b>. Для удобства можно воспользоваться &lt;a href="http://filezilla-project.org/">FileZilla&lt;/a>
или любой другой аналогичной программой. Создайте на сервере папку, из
которой вы хотите чтобы работал MT, и перенесите разархивированный
архив, сохранив его структуру. Файлы можно скопировать в корень вашего
сервиса, и тогда MT будет доступна по адресу вашдомен.com или же в
папку, и тогда MT будет доступна по адресу вашдомен.com/вашапапка/.
Если у вас не очень быстрый интернет, то можете выпить сколько то
кружек чая с пирожными, пока копируются файлы&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="http://www.superxm.com/images/mt4-installation-05.jpg" height="410" width="294" />&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;b>5. Устанавливаем правильный chmod на файлы&lt;/b>. Не пугайтесь, ничего
сложного - нужно лишь выбрать файлы и изменить их свойства. Сложности
тут возникнут только лишь если сервер на котором вы пытаетесь это
сделать, принадлежит Пентагону, или же находится в каком-либо другом
месте и админ страдает параноей по отношению к безопасности. Если вы
используете FileZilla то этот процесс выглядит очень просто. Писать
даже ничего не буду - все видно на картинках:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="http://www.superxm.com/images/mt4-installation-06.jpg" height="240" width="208" />&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="http://www.superxm.com/images/mt4-installation-07.jpg" height="329" width="457" />&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;b>6. А сейчас настало время установки&lt;/b>. Наберите в вашем броузере
адрес, куда вы закачали &lt;i>Movable Type&lt;/i>. Это &lt;b>вашдомен.com&lt;/b> или
&lt;b>вашдомен.com/вашадиректория /&lt;/b> или что-либо еще в зависимости от того,
куда вы разместили файлы. И вы должны будете увидеть это.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="http://www.superxm.com/images/mt4-installation-08.jpg" height="300" width="278" />&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Подождите 5-10 секунд, и вас автоматически перекинет на страничку для инсталяции:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="http://www.superxm.com/images/mt4-installation-09.jpg" height="150" width="268" />&lt;/p>
&lt;p>И переходите к следующему этапу, на котором система проверит различные вещи&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="http://www.superxm.com/images/mt4-installation-10.jpg" height="219" width="270" />&lt;/p>
&lt;p>И если все в порядке (вы ведь все правильно сделали?) вводим в
соответствующие поля сохраненную нами в первом пункте информацию (вы
ведь ее сохранили, да?). Заполнив все жмем '&lt;i>test connection&lt;/i>':&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="http://www.superxm.com/images/mt4-installation-11.jpg" height="419" width="270" />&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Отлично, мы настроили подключение с базой данных, и приступим к следующему шагу&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="http://www.superxm.com/images/mt4-installation-12.jpg" height="208" width="270" />&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Где нас попросят настроить почту. Нет проблем - выбираем "&lt;i>sendmail"&lt;/i>,
вводим наш &lt;i>email &lt;/i>и проверяем что оно работает. Для этого жмите '&lt;i>send
test email&lt;/i>' и проверяйте вашу электронную почту. Продолжаем наши пляски
с бубном дальше.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="http://www.superxm.com/images/mt4-installation-13.jpg" height="226" width="270" />&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="http://www.superxm.com/images/mt4-installation-14.jpg" height="302" width="270" />&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Вот мы уже почти подобрались к концу. Конфигурационный файл создан, жмем '&lt;i>continue&lt;/i>':&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="http://www.superxm.com/images/mt4-installation-15.jpg" height="254" width="270" />&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;b>7. Теперь нам надо создать свою учетную запись в системе&lt;/b>. Вы в ней
админ, и вольны ввести то, что желаете. Не забудьте указать вш
работающий email адрес, ну и не забудьте придуманный пароль.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="http://www.superxm.com/images/mt4-installation-16.jpg" height="449" width="270" />&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Дальше необходимо ввести базовую информацию о вашем блоге. Его название, адрес, (url).Настроив, жмите "&lt;i>Finish install&lt;/i>"&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="http://www.superxm.com/images/mt4-installation-17.jpg" height="367" width="270" />&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Какое-то время смотрите на&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="http://www.superxm.com/images/mt4-installation-18.jpg" height="304" width="270" />&lt;/p>
&lt;p>И затем появится информация о том, что инсталяция закончена.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="http://www.superxm.com/images/mt4-installation-19.jpg" height="290" width="270" />&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;b>8. Вы можете зайти нажав на 'sign in..." и попадете в зону
администрирования платформой.&lt;/b> Откуда вы сможете изучать и управлять
Movable Type 4. Для того, чтобы иметь возможность всегда попасть в
админку MT используйте адрес "&lt;b>www.yoursite.com/mt.cgi&lt;/b>" или другой, в
зависимости от того, куда вы установили MT.&lt;/p>&lt;a href="http://www.daarh.net/2007/10/ustanovka-movable-type-4-shag-za-shagom.html" target="_blank">Источник&lt;/a></description></item><item><title>Приветствие!</title><link>https://dmitrijev.ru/2008/07/privetstvie.php/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jul 2008 05:42:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dmitrijev.ru/2008/07/privetstvie.php/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;b>&lt;font style="font-size: 1.25em;">Приветствую&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;i>всех&lt;/i>, &lt;u>кто&lt;/u> &lt;strike>пометил&lt;/strike> посетил &lt;a href="http://www.dmitrijev.ru/">мою домашнюю страничку&lt;/a>!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Расширенный текст&lt;br />&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Шутка</title><link>https://dmitrijev.ru/2008/04/shutka.php/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2008 12:32:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dmitrijev.ru/2008/04/shutka.php/</guid><description>&lt;p>Мая пашутилло&lt;/p>
&lt;p>о, е&amp;hellip;&lt;br />&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Frequently Asked Question</title><link>https://dmitrijev.ru/2004/03/frequently-asked-question.php/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2004 02:08:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dmitrijev.ru/2004/03/frequently-asked-question.php/</guid><description>&lt;p>Recently Movable Style has attracted quite a few visitors (current at
around 200-300 unique visitors per day), and sorry if I have not
updated the site or respond to your comments. I have been &lt;em>busy&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>just moved to a new place that needs lots of work, wife expecting a
baby in July, lots of demand at work, working with new students at
church, etc. I will try to answer some of your questions this entry,
and hopefully when I finally have more time on hand (if ever), I would
go back to work on more styles.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3>FAQ Index&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.movablestyle.com/archives/2004-03.php#20040302-1">Can I use the stylesheets that I downloaded from Movable Style on my own blog site(s)?&lt;/a>&lt;/li>&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.movablestyle.com/archives/2004-03.php#20040302-2">How do I use the stylesheets on Movable Style?&lt;/a>&lt;/li>&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.movablestyle.com/archives/2004-03.php#20040302-3">How are the stylesheets licensed?&lt;/a>&lt;/li>&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.movablestyle.com/archives/2004-03.php#20040302-4">How do I attribute to Movable Style?&lt;/a>&lt;/li>&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.movablestyle.com/archives/2004-03.php#20040302-5">There is no update for &lt;em>ages&lt;/em>! What's the future direction for this site?&lt;/a>&lt;/li>&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.movablestyle.com/archives/2004-03.php#20040302-6">How do I contact you, this "scotty" guy?&lt;/a>&lt;/li>&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.movablestyle.com/archives/2004-03.php#20040315-1">How is the style switcher implemented?&lt;/a>&lt;/li>&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.movablestyle.com/archives/2004-03.php" name="20040302-1">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;b>Can I use the stylesheets that I downloaded from Movable Style on my own blog site(s)?&lt;/b>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The initial intention of developing this site is to &lt;em>share&lt;/em>
some of the stylesheets I designed with people who have just started
blogging, do not want to tinker too much Movable Type templates, and
want to have a style that is different from the stock ones. All
stylesheets here are created to be shared, so please use them!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.movablestyle.com/archives/2004-03.php" name="20040302-2">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;b>How do I use the stylesheets on Movable Style?&lt;/b>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The stylesheets are designed for the Movable Type default templates. Here outlines how you can use the styles.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>&lt;li>Go to the &lt;a href="http://www.movablestyle.com/">index page&lt;/a>,
and you should see a side-bar section called "Styles". Use the
selection list to change the current style to the one you desire, and
then click on &lt;img src="http://web.archive.org/web/20040405163550/http://www.movablestyle.com/image/download.png" alt="Download File" /> &lt;a href="http://www.movablestyle.com/styles/MovableType-Clean/styles-site.css">Download Style&lt;/a> to download the stylesheet and optional image files.&lt;/li>&lt;li>If the file downloaded contains only one single file '&lt;tt>style-site.css&lt;/tt>', go to the next step. Alternatively, you would download a file called '&lt;tt>style-site.zip&lt;/tt>'
that contains the CSS and other media files (usually images). Upload
those image files (.JPG or .PNG) to your blog site, and move them to
the same folder as your index page. You can use Movable Type's &lt;a href="http://www.movabletype.org/docs/mtmanual-uploading.htm">Uploading File&lt;/a> feature to achieve that.&lt;/li>&lt;li>Now, replace your current '&lt;tt>style-site.css&lt;/tt>' with the one you have downloaded. In a stock Movable Type installation, you would need to:
&lt;ol>&lt;li>Go to Manage Weblog page, and then click on "Templates" on the left-hand side.&lt;/li>&lt;li>There should be an item "Stylesheet" under table "Index templates". It defaults to output to file '&lt;tt>style-site.css&lt;/tt>'. Click on the link.&lt;/li>&lt;li>Replace the content inside "Template Body" with the content of your new '&lt;tt>style-site.css&lt;/tt>', and then press "Save" and "Rebuild".&lt;/li>&lt;/ol>
&lt;/li>&lt;li>Try to reload your weblog, and it should now be formatted wit the new style.&lt;/li>&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.movablestyle.com/archives/2004-03.php" name="20040302-3">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;b>How are the stylesheets licensed?&lt;/b>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>See &lt;a href="http://www.movablestyle.com/archives/000015.php">this article&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Currently stylesheets on Movable Style are dual licensed with
Creative Common Attribution and GNU General Public License. Generally,
if you want to use it on a blog site, please use CC and attribute this
site. If you want to bundle the stylesheets with a software, for
example another blog tool with modified styles, then please follow the
guideline on GPL.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.movablestyle.com/archives/2004-03.php" name="20040302-4">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;b>How do I attribute to Movable Style?&lt;/b>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From the license it is &lt;em>required&lt;/em> that you provide
attribution to Movable Style when you use one or more styles from this
site. I am not looking for a permanent spot on your site, but a small
blog entry will do. For example,&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
Hi. I have changed the stylesheet for this site, and I got it from &lt;a href="http://www.movablestyle.com/">Movable Style&lt;/a>! Blah blah blah...
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>There is &lt;em>no&lt;/em> logo, "official" slogan, etc. Just say where you got the blog from and that's it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.movablestyle.com/archives/2004-03.php" name="20040302-5">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;b>There is no update for &lt;em>ages&lt;/em>! What's the future direction for this site?&lt;/b>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well. I am busy. &lt;em>Really busy&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I initially designed this site to share my own styles, and then last
couple of months I have been receiving emails from people submitting
their styles. As I stated before that managing a site with other
people's contribution can add quite a bit of burden on myself, but I
think it might be something that can better benefit the community so it
would the direction that Movable Style would move to.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I need to work out a way to manage the licenses (or force everyone
to agree on CC Attribution + GPL), plus some scripts for people to
submit their styles. Technically it should be an easy task, but I just
need time to sit down and code it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.movablestyle.com/archives/2004-03.php" name="#20040302-6">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;b>How do I contact you, this "scotty" guy?&lt;/b>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Use the &lt;a href="http://scott.yang.id.au/contact.php">contact page&lt;/a> on my own blog site.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.movablestyle.com/archives/2004-03.php" name="#20040315-1">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;b>How is the style switcher implemented?&lt;/b>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The style switcher on Movable Style is implemented using some PHP scripts. More detailed implementation can be found in &lt;a href="http://www.movablestyle.com/archives/000017.php">this blog entry&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lines with a Modern Look</title><link>https://dmitrijev.ru/2004/01/lines-with-a-modern-look.php/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2004 04:02:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dmitrijev.ru/2004/01/lines-with-a-modern-look.php/</guid><description>&lt;p>I have just created a new style that utilises &lt;tt>position: relative&lt;/tt>
to move the display of date to the side of the blog entries. Adding
borders of different width, and I am trying to give it a modern look.
Most of the time is spent on getting it to work on Internet Explorer,
which makes funny rendering when I started adding some paddings. At the
end, I figured that it is better to use &lt;tt>margin&lt;/tt> than &lt;tt>padding&lt;/tt>, in cases where both of them create the same effect, as somehow IE calculates the position better with it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Or better, just switch to Mozilla to gain much better web surfing experience.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
Apply &lt;a href="http://www.movablestyle.com/archives/2004-01.php?style=Modern-Lines">Modern Lines&lt;/a> style
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Another thing is the style submissions. Although I took &lt;a href="http://www.movablestyle.com/archives/000013.php">one and published it&lt;/a>
previously, but I have decided that I'll dedicate this site for the
styles that I have created. It is just getting too hard to keep track
(and doing quality control on all the variations) of all the styles you
guys have submitted. Plus all the confusing copyright issue that I need
to deal with. Thank you if you have emailed me your style sheet! But I
think I am not aiming to build a styles repository from the beginning.
I'll rather to keep this place a small collection of styles of my own.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dual License for Movable Styles</title><link>https://dmitrijev.ru/2004/01/dual-license-for-movable-style.php/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2004 11:03:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dmitrijev.ru/2004/01/dual-license-for-movable-style.php/</guid><description>&lt;p>Thanks to suggestion from &lt;a href="http://www.eadz.co.nz/">Eaden&lt;/a>, cascading style sheets on Movable Style will be dual licensed. Currently it is licensed under &lt;a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/1.0/">Creative Common Attribution 1.0&lt;/a>, which requires everyone who uses of MT styles created by me to give credit to me. That includes all the styles listed except &lt;a href="http://www.movablestyle.com/archives/000002.php">Movable Type default styles&lt;/a> (copyright &lt;a href="http://www.sixapart.com/">Six Aprt&lt;/a>) and &lt;a href="http://www.movablestyle.com/archives/000013.php">Lovingrey&lt;/a> (copyright &lt;a href="http://wavez.weblogs.us/">Wavez&lt;/a>). Now these styles can also be licensed under &lt;a href="http://www.gnu.org/copyleft/gpl.html">GNU Public License 2&lt;/a>, so that it can be modified and included into another weblogging tool, like PHP/Smarty based &lt;a href="http://www.bblog.com/">BBlog&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Complicated? I think so as well. I am by no means a license expert, and
I have never heard of GPLing a CSS file. But somehow this arrangement
makes everything works nicely - the author of these styles get his
credit, yet these styles can be compatible to applications that suffer
from this GPL virus. Oh I mean applications that stand for the true
spirit of Free Software.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lovingrey</title><link>https://dmitrijev.ru/2003/12/lovingrey.php/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2003 12:59:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dmitrijev.ru/2003/12/lovingrey.php/</guid><description>&lt;p>We have the first style submission yesterday. &lt;a href="http://wavez.weblogs.us/">Wavez&lt;/a> modified my &lt;a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20040202204720/http://www.movablestyle.com/archives/archives/000008.php">Purple Orange&lt;/a> theme, and created a dark-grey'ish Movable Type style called "Lovingrey", and have requested to be included here.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>Apply &lt;a href="http://www.movablestyle.com/archives/2003-12.php?style=Lovingrey">Lovingrey&lt;/a> style&lt;br />&lt;br />&lt;span class="mt-enclosure mt-enclosure-image" style="display: inline;">&lt;img alt="lovingrey.gif" src="http://www.dmitrijev.ru/2008/07/29/lovingrey.gif" class="mt-image-none" style="" height="197" width="300" />&lt;/span>&lt;br />&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I do like to take more submission, especially original styles :)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Enter The Matrix</title><link>https://dmitrijev.ru/2003/11/enter-the-matrix.php/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2003 03:57:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dmitrijev.ru/2003/11/enter-the-matrix.php/</guid><description>&lt;p>Here's a new Movale Type style that I've created with an &lt;a href="http://whatisthematrix.warnerbros.com/rl-img/poster7.jpg">image&lt;/a> from the &lt;a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20040202204221/http://us.imdb.com/title/tt0234215/">Matrix Reloaded&lt;/a> poster.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
Apply &lt;a href="http://www.movablestyle.com/archives/2003-11.php?style=Matrix-Code">Matrix Code&lt;/a> style&lt;br />&lt;span class="mt-enclosure mt-enclosure-image" style="display: inline;">&lt;img alt="matrix-code.gif" src="http://www.dmitrijev.ru/2008/07/29/matrix-code.gif" class="mt-image-none" style="" height="197" width="300" />&lt;/span>&lt;br />
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I noticed that it is the first dark style (white on black) that I&amp;rsquo;ve created for this site. The main &lt;tt>&amp;lt;body /&amp;gt;&lt;/tt>
element has a background image faded into black across the top, and the
content/container pane also has a similar background image at the
bottom. With the title elements, there&amp;rsquo;s a transparent 8-bit PNG file
that masks out every other pixel to create that &amp;ldquo;shaded&amp;rdquo; effect. Too
bad that Internet Explorer does not have the alpha support in 32bit PNG
files.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Style with Mac Stripe</title><link>https://dmitrijev.ru/2003/10/style-with-mac-stripe.php/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2003 03:20:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dmitrijev.ru/2003/10/style-with-mac-stripe.php/</guid><description>&lt;p>I have been trying to come up with a style that assembles the look of &lt;a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20040405155230/http://www.apple.com/">Apple&lt;/a>'s
operating system, but has found it quite difficult without modifying
the template file, as the UI is quite graphical intensive with lots of
images pasted here and there. Maybe it is just my CSS skill not mature
enough&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At the end, I decided just to ripped the original "Clean" style of
Movable Type, and then applies the background stripes in varies places,
and call this new style "Mac Stripe"&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>Apply &lt;a href="http://www.movablestyle.com/archives/2003-10.php?style=Mac-Stripe">Mac Stripe&lt;/a> style.&lt;br />&lt;span class="mt-enclosure mt-enclosure-image" style="display: inline;">&lt;img alt="mac-stripe.gif" src="http://www.dmitrijev.ru/2008/07/29/mac-stripe.gif" class="mt-image-none" style="" height="197" width="300" />&lt;/span>&lt;br />&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Hopefully I won't be followed up by a email from the lawyers from Apple...&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Moving Site</title><link>https://dmitrijev.ru/2003/10/moving-site.php/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2003 06:10:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dmitrijev.ru/2003/10/moving-site.php/</guid><description>&lt;p>I have recently registered the domain &lt;tt>movablestyle.com&lt;/tt>, and
will serve this site at that same domain, using a separate MovableType
database. It will still be on the same old home build Linux server
through ADSL through.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The reasons of making the move:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>&lt;li>I have got quite a few hits on this site, so I want it to be separated from my &lt;a href="http://scott.yang.id.au/">main site&lt;/a> to track traffic independently.&lt;/li>&lt;li>Having its own domain looks more &lt;em>professional&lt;/em>, even though the site will never be commercial and will be based on good will.&lt;/li>&lt;li>I need the MT installation and the site to be on the same domain to
track some cookies, which enables me to display the same style sheet in
comment/traceback listing pages. This part has not been implemented
yet...&lt;/li>&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Preferred/Alternate Stylesheet</title><link>https://dmitrijev.ru/2003/10/preferredalternate-stylesheet.php/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2003 07:13:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dmitrijev.ru/2003/10/preferredalternate-stylesheet.php/</guid><description>&lt;p>One feature in the latest &lt;a href="http://www.mozilla.org/products/firebird/">Mozilla Firebird&lt;/a> is the ability to easily switch between different &lt;a href="http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/present/styles.html#h-14.3.1">alternate stylesheets&lt;/a>
provided by the document. It allows the author of the site to provide
personalised look &amp;lsquo;n&amp;rsquo; feel, without changing the HTML source
dynamically. I think it also makes sense for MovableStyle to implement
this standard, by including all the alternate style sheets in the HTML.&lt;/p>
&lt;p style="text-align: center;">&lt;img src="http://web.archive.org/web/20040405155230/http://www.movablestyle.com/image/firebird-style.png" alt="MozillaFirebird" />&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Obviously, switching between alternate stylesheets requires browser
support, and MSIE certainly does not provide this functionality. So my
next step will be providing a &lt;a href="http://www.alistapart.com/stories/alternate/">Javascript alternative&lt;/a>, and apply it on the drop down box. Switching styles should no longer require reloading the current page again.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;b>Update&lt;/b>:
I might need to turn this feature off at some stage, as
Mozilla/Firebird/Firefox will try to load every stylesheets declared as
alternative styles, even though it might not have been used. It would
not be feasible when the number of styles increases, and it does take
out the bandwidth a bit.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hitting with a bit or warmth</title><link>https://dmitrijev.ru/2003/10/hitting-with-a-bit-or-warmth.php/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2003 03:08:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dmitrijev.ru/2003/10/hitting-with-a-bit-or-warmth.php/</guid><description>&lt;p>For the themes that I have created so far, you can see that I
usually favour bright cold colour (either green or blue with white
background). I decided that I want to try out something different
today, and a warm orange colour as the main theme. I added some purple
strips just to mark out certain parts of the page to make them look
"distinctive". So there you go - my first attempt to add some warmth
into my collection of MovableType style sheets.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;a href="http://www.movablestyle.com/archives/2003-10.php?style=Orange-Purple">Orange Purple&lt;/a>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I just realised that I am very bad at naming things...&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Slashdot Style</title><link>https://dmitrijev.ru/2003/10/slashdot-style.php/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2003 05:06:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dmitrijev.ru/2003/10/slashdot-style.php/</guid><description>&lt;p>I have been reading &lt;a href="http://slashdot.org/">Slashdot&lt;/a>
for at least 5-6 years I think, and it has to be one of the pioneers of
weblogs. Even through it pushes out dozens of technology-related news
everyday, Slashdot's HTML is still using HTML3.2 with lots of in-line
formattings that are obsolete in today's HTML4/XHTML era.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is actually not that hard porting the look and feel of Slashdot
over to Movable Type, and I think more and more I felt the "real
challenge" comes from the MT's default template. There are many tricks
that I would like to do but would require changes to the default
template...&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anyway. Here it is. I still haven't figured out a way to make the #links side bar to maximise to 100% of the height...&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;a href="http://www.movablestyle.com/archives/2003-10.php?style=Slashdot">Slashdot Theme&lt;/a>&lt;br />&lt;span class="mt-enclosure mt-enclosure-image" style="display: inline;">&lt;img alt="slashdot.gif" src="http://www.dmitrijev.ru/2008/07/29/slashdot.gif" class="mt-image-none" style="" height="197" width="300" />&lt;/span>&lt;br />
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Note - this style contains 2 .png files that needs to be unzipped into the same directory as the .css&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Plain Blue</title><link>https://dmitrijev.ru/2003/10/plain-blue.php/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2003 03:04:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dmitrijev.ru/2003/10/plain-blue.php/</guid><description>&lt;p>Getting sick of border of different shade wrapping around each
other? This style is much plainer than the previous boxed styles. It
places the #links side bar to the right hand side, flowing down from
the very top of the page. Somehow I cannot get it to maximised to 100%
of the page height...&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;a href="http://www.movablestyle.com/archives/2003-10.php?style=Plain-Blue">Plain Blue Theme&lt;/a>&lt;br />&lt;br />&lt;span class="mt-enclosure mt-enclosure-image" style="display: inline;">&lt;img alt="plain-blue.gif" src="http://www.dmitrijev.ru/2008/07/29/plain-blue.gif" class="mt-image-none" style="" height="197" width="300" />&lt;/span>&lt;br />
&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>Another boxed style</title><link>https://dmitrijev.ru/2008/07/privetstvie.php/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2003 01:01:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dmitrijev.ru/2008/07/privetstvie.php/</guid><description>&lt;p>Well. There is nothing new in this one, but turning the &lt;a href="http://www.movablestyle.com/archives/000004.php">previous style&lt;/a> into a different colour theme, to prove that it is actually easy to take an existing style and change its colours.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;a href="http://www.movablestyle.com/archives/2003-10.php?style=Boxed-Green">Boxed Theme in Green&lt;/a>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>A boxed style</title><link>https://dmitrijev.ru/2003/09/a-boxed-style.php/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2003 02:58:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dmitrijev.ru/2003/09/a-boxed-style.php/</guid><description>&lt;p>I've created a style that has bolders in neverly every DIV's, to
help me to visualise the actual boundary. It has a gray scale theme,
and #content and #links are positioned using absolute position. Here's
the theme:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>&lt;a href="http://www.movablestyle.com/archives/2003-09.php?style=Boxed">Boxed Theme&lt;/a>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I still need to test its appearance/browser-compatibility under:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>&lt;li>&lt;strike>Mozilla Firebird 0.6.1 on Windows&lt;/strike>&lt;/li>&lt;li>&lt;strike>Mozilla 1.4 on Windows&lt;/strike>&lt;/li>&lt;li>&lt;strike>Internet Explorer SP1&lt;/strike>&lt;/li>&lt;li>&lt;strike>Camino 0.7 on Mac OS X&lt;/strike>&lt;/li>&lt;li>&lt;strike>Safari on Mac OS X&lt;/strike>&lt;/li>&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>TypePad-Look-Alike Stylesheet</title><link>https://dmitrijev.ru/2003/09/typepadlookalike-stylesheet.php/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2003 02:56:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dmitrijev.ru/2003/09/typepadlookalike-stylesheet.php/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is the first stylesheet that I've done for MovableStyle site!
Well. The look 'n' feel is nothing original, but imitate many existing
sites on &lt;a href="http://www.typepad.com/">TypePad.com&lt;/a>, including Claudine's beta testing site.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It was a quick hack job, and I think quite a few parts still does
not appear to work. I think I'll come back later to get the comment
listing/preview and trackback listing to work. There are also some
glitches due to differences between the MovableType and TypePad
templates.&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;First of all, I cannot get
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>the banner and content to centred on the page, due to the way
MovableType stock template is structured. On TypePad, it is structured
like this:&lt;/p>&lt;/p>
&lt;pre type="code"> &amp;lt;body&amp;gt;&lt;br /> &amp;lt;div id="container"&amp;gt;&lt;br /> &amp;lt;div id="banner" /&amp;gt;&lt;br /> &amp;lt;div id="content" /&amp;gt;&lt;br /> &amp;lt;div id="right" /&amp;gt;&lt;br /> &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&lt;br /> &amp;lt;/body&amp;gt;&lt;br />&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>Where as in MT, the index page template has the following structure:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre type="code"> &amp;lt;body&amp;gt;&lt;br /> &amp;lt;div id="banner" /&amp;gt;&lt;br /> &amp;lt;div id="content" /&amp;gt;&lt;br /> &amp;lt;div id="links" /&amp;gt;&lt;br /> &amp;lt;/body&amp;gt;&lt;br />&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>The contents that need to be centred are not wrapped inside another DIV with &lt;tt>margin-left&lt;/tt> and &lt;tt>margin-right&lt;/tt> set to &lt;tt>auto&lt;/tt>, and so far I have not found a way to move &lt;tt>#content&lt;/tt> and &lt;tt>#links&lt;/tt>
next to each other yet centred in the page. I realise that I could use
IE's expression style to calculate the left/right margin, but then
Mozilla users will loose out. At the end, I just set up a fixed margin
(10%) on the left/right.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Default Styles from Movable Type</title><link>https://dmitrijev.ru/2003/09/default-styles-from-movable-ty.php/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2003 05:52:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dmitrijev.ru/2003/09/default-styles-from-movable-ty.php/</guid><description>&lt;p>These are the default stylesheets &lt;a href="http://www.movabletype.org/default-styles.shtml">listed&lt;/a> on the Movable Type website. These are probably the most common styles you&amp;rsquo;ll see around the web.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.movablestyle.com/archives/2003-09.php?style=MovableType-Clean">Clean&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.movablestyle.com/archives/2003-09.php?style=MovableType-Georgia-Blue">Georgia Blue&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.movablestyle.com/archives/2003-09.php?style=MovableType-Gettyburg">Gettyburg&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.movablestyle.com/archives/2003-09.php?style=MovableType-Plain-Jane">Plain Jane&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.movablestyle.com/archives/2003-09.php?style=MovableType-Rusty">Rusty&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.movablestyle.com/archives/2003-09.php?style=MovableType-Trendy">Trendy&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>These styles should at least get this site started...&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>First Entry</title><link>https://dmitrijev.ru/2003/09/first-entry.php/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2003 02:47:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dmitrijev.ru/2003/09/first-entry.php/</guid><description>&lt;p>I am starting this new blog to collect good CSS style sheets that
work with the stock Movable Type template. Movable Type is powerful,
and with its template engine, one can customise an unique blogsite by
editing the templates. However, many people with a blogsite on the
Internet simply aren't capable of working with HTML and CSS. Some
people aren't really bothered with it. &lt;br />&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So at the end, there are many
MovableType powered blogsite on the net that are just look alike
(including many sites listed on &lt;a href="http://focuser.net/">FOCUSer.net&lt;/a>).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The purpose of this site is to create a collection of good CSS that is suitable for the &lt;em>stock Movable Type template&lt;/em>.
There is nothing wrong with the stock template - a two pane designe in
validated XHTML. So I hope people can simple grab the CSS files and
paste right into their "&lt;tt>styles-site.css&lt;/tt>" template to transform their site.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Also, to help people test out different style sheets, this site needs to be easily skinnable. I'll talk more about that later.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, I shall go back hacking more CSS....&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>